<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>elm-conf 2016</title>
    <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/</link>
    <description>Recent content on elm-conf 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 08:26:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.elm-conf.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Griffith</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/matthew-griffith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 08:26:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/matthew-griffith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Games and rich applications present a compelling use-case for Elm, but managing
dynamic animations can quickly become complicated. Here’s how to succinctly
express animation pipelines using the elm-style-animation library and how to
architect your animation code in a readable, extensible manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll cover…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What options are available for animation in Elm and when it makes sense to use
them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to tackle real-world animation using the elm-style-animation library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A straightforward way to organize animations so that they are readable,
extensible, and easily integrated into the Elm architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re here, you probably already know that Elm is a solid base for building
complex applications. You’ll come away from this talk with the tools to make
those applications gorgeous as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Griffith is a developer with a passion for intuitive interfaces. Then
again, he’s also a data scientist who’s worked in cheminformatics for the past
eight years and loves a good dataset. More recently he developed the
elm-style-animation library in his pursuit of creating maintainable, beautiful
apps in Elm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew is a developer in residence at Cornell Tech in Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abadi Kurniawan</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/abadi-kurniawan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 13:48:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/abadi-kurniawan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Elm pretty much solves the tool and framework fatigue when starting a new
front-end project, we still have the same issue for the back-end. Using Horizon
in your Elm app can help alleviate the pain by reducing the amount of work you
have to do in the back-end, so you can write more Elm code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When starting a new project in JavaScript, you’re most likely going to spend a
lot of time choosing the tools and frameworks to use, and then spend more time
configuring them. Elm pretty much solves this problem by providing all the
tooling you need out of the box, and by The Elm Community’s preference to have
one way to do things, so you don’t have choose between 100 different packages
just to solve 1 problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, how about the back-end? You still have to choose all the stacks; from
database, web server, programming language, and the framework. At least, until
we have server side Elm, we still have the same problem here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if you don’t have to worry about the back-end, and can just
focus on writing Elm code and be happy? We can do that with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://horizon.io/&#34;&gt;Horizon&lt;/a&gt;. Horizon is an open source server designed for
building real time application without writing any back-end code. With Horizon,
all you need to do is to run the Horizon server, start writing Elm code, and be
happy and productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abadi is a senior developer at Engage Software, a St. Louis based software
company. He has been writing Elm in production since March 2016. He’s the author
of &lt;a href=&#34;https://abadi199.github.io/elm-creditcard/&#34;&gt;Elm Credit Card&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://package.elm-lang.org/packages/abadi199/elm-input-extra/latest/&#34;&gt;Elm Input Extra&lt;/a&gt;.
Outside of work, he spends time with his wife and son, and works on making his
house smarter so he can spend more time with his family and less on doing
chores.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Schomay</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/jeff-schomay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:26:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/jeff-schomay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elm Architecture works great for apps, but how about for building a game
framework? This talk looks at using the strengths of Elm to build the open
source “Elm Narrative Engine,” including an example interactive story and the
challenges and solutions faced in using Elm to make a framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a programmer by profession and passion, but with a background and schooling
in film production and screenwriting, I have forever been drawn to playing and
making games with strong narrative components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have played, studied and written screenplays, classic text adventures, visual
novels, point-and-click adventures, and other storytelling game mediums and
tools, comparing and contrasting the different types of stories each affords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a self-described “Ambassador of Elm,” I decided to use the strengths of Elm
to build a storytelling game framework called the “Elm Narrative Engine” for
telling the types of interactive stories I want to tell based on all of my
research in this area. The games it makes would be less about modeling spacial
navigation and branching narratives over time, and more about modeling a story
that unfolds like a puzzle, like a cross between a traditional novel and a
point-and-click adventure. The design goals include a clean and simple way to
author stories as a developer, and a simple interaction style for players,
keeping the focus squarely on the text-based narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk looks briefly at some of existing options in this area, such as Inform
7 for writing text adventures, RenPy for making visual novels, and Twine for
“non-linear hypertext narratives,” comparing and contrasting their approaches to
the Elm Narrative Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a demo of a fully-featured story written on the Elm Narrative Engine, I
will dive into the code and the technical considerations and challenges faced in
approaching building the engine with Elm. I will give a lot of attention to the
differences of building a framework in Elm, as opposed to an app or library and
the challenges this brings, including these topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How The Elm Architecture applies to designing a framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treating the engine as a “run time” and the client as an “embedded app”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make use of types to build a clean client “api”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data structures and state-machines for narrative data and internationalization
consideration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the “time traveling debugger” technique for “rewinding” narrative
branches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Elm’s Commands for adding multi-media to a story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the talk, the audience should have a good appreciation for the
technical and design decisions in interactive storytelling, and a concrete grasp
on designing a framework in Elm and how to define the boundaries between client
and framework code. As the engine is open source, I encourage pull requests, and
my hope is that some of the members of the audience will create their own
narrative stories on the Elm Narrative Engine for myself an the rest of the
community to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a professional entertainer and a professional programmer. I’ve written
screenplays and I’ve written mobile apps. I’ve been a director of photography
and a technical lead. I’ve started more than one juggling club and more than one
hack night meetup. I’ve lived in multiple places in the US and multiple places
in Europe. I love art and I love vim. I preach the power of creativity and the
power of functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find fulfillment and perfection in living in two worlds, and combining them
into one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joël Quenneville</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/joel-quenneville/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/joel-quenneville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dive into Elm’s random generators on a quest to build a historically accurate
Roman random name generator for the goddess Juno, based on a series of dependent
and independent constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are an ancient software engineer. Juno, the Roman goddess of marriage and
fertility, surprises you by walking into your office and offering you an
assignment. Overseeing the birth and naming of all Roman children is becoming a
large and monotonous task. She is looking to modernize and automate. Will you
build her a piece of software to randomly generate valid information for a Roman
child?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on the quest to complete this project using Elm’s random generators.
Along the way, we will see how to create complex generators out of simple ones,
how to handle dependent and independent constraints, and how to work with
percentages and Maybe. You will leave with a firm grasp of how Elm handles
randomness in a functional manner and the confidence to implement your own
generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joël is a software developer at thoughtbot. He is passionate about best
practices and building excellent software. Although he got his start with
dynamically typed imperative languages, he has recently become fascinated with
the statically typed functional world and Elm in particular. Outside of
programming, Joël loves to study history. He often combines these two interests
together to play with historically-themed software side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jessica Kerr</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/jessica-kerr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:18:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/jessica-kerr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the explicitness and structure of Elm. I don’t love typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mechanical friend can help with both: smart templates modify code to perform
common tasks, and Github PRs keep this safe and editor-independent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See an Elm project created and grown with strategically placed automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the explicitness and the consistent structure of Elm code and the Elm
Architecture. Sometimes I don’t love the typing involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elm is well-suited to code generation. We like to generate code (like with
html2elm) and modify it. The automation doesn’t have to end there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session will demonstrate growing an Elm app with the help of a smarter
templating engine and Github pull requests. Tasks like “add a new component” or
“start using elm-test” or “change a service contract” happen safely and
mechanically, outside of your favorite editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep all the structure, skip some of the tedium. See another reason that Elm can
be our most productive language system yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica Kerr (better known as Jessitron) works on deployment at Stripe. She
writes Ruby, Scala, Go, you name it. She speaks at conferences in the US,
Europe, and Australia. She podcasts as a Ruby Rogue, parents two daughters, and
writes Elm for fun. Look for her in St. Louis, San Francisco, and wherever
functional programming and silliness meet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tessa Kelly</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/tessa-kelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:06:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/tessa-kelly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elegant data structures are different across programming languages, and creating
them should be approached differently. Leverage Elm’s union types to build
simple and readable structures, beginning with binary trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a binary tree might be a familiar task in JavaScript or Ruby, and it
might seem like a very similar problem in Elm. While it’s possible to create
data structures in Elm that are very similar to ones written in languages that
aren’t strictly functional and that don’t have types, there are better
approaches. This talk will explore a few different implementations and
recommendations, and assumes an audience without extensive academic ML-family
language experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a software engineer at NoRedInk, Tessa reads, writes, and extends a lot of
Elm code. Before joining NoRedInk, Tessa spent her time thinking about
curricula, learning, and engagement in the context of teaching web development.
She holds a BA in Mathematics from New York University, where she also minored
in History and in Middle Eastern Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murphy Randle</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/murphy-randle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 10:57:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/murphy-randle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk combines the power of Elm and Elixir’s Phoenix to turn Twitter into a
platform for live crowd-sourced music composition. We’ll cover Elm and Elixir
channels, custom DSL parsing in Elm, and driving the Web Audio API through Elm’s
native inter-op abstraction: ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to demonstrate the power of coordinating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parser combinators, and Elm’s bogdanp/elm-combine library for transforming
strings into data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elm’s standard application architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ports (Elm’s abstraction for interacting with its host language, in this case,
Javascript)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Phoenix Web framework and its real-time channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elm’s integration with Phoenix channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tone.js for making music with the Web Audio API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For illustrative purposes we’ll suppose we are a consultancy, and a client has
just approached us with the need to turn tweets into music. She has come up with
a compact musical notation that will fit a good chunk of music into 140
characters, and she wants us to teach the browser to play the music encoded in
that notation. But that’s not all. Her vision includes a client that streams in
tweets, parsing them and queueing them up to be played as they happen,
ultimately allowing users to listen to a never-ending piece of real-time music,
composed by a symphony of twitter users world-wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chief smile officer and executive code whisperer at Kuali, Murphy makes tools to
support higher education. He’s an Egghead.io instructor, a full-stack JS dev,
and a functional programming padawan. He comes from a background in animation
technologies, specializing in rendering and pipeline development. If you look
carefully, you might see his name in the credits of a film.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke Westby</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/luke-westby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 10:54:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/luke-westby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have ADHD and struggle to stay focused on things. This has actually been
helpful in learning JS since things change as quickly as my attention does, but
it makes it hard to finish things. Elm pushes out distractions so I can focus,
and at last the first side-project I’ve ever completed is in Elm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived with ADHD my whole life. There are certainly worse things to live
with, but our world is tailored to people who can concentrate – tasks and
deadlines drive our working society. I’ve spent most of my illustrious career
working with JS, where things change just as quickly as my attention, and it’s
been hard to feel a sense of grounding or belonging. Then I found Elm. Even
though Elm wasn’t designed for people with ADHD explicitly, it is the best
language for those who do to build applications. With Elm, the distractions fall
away and I am able to channel more of the craziness that I experience in my head
into useful work. In this talk I will share my experiences as such a person with
all of you. I hope you’ll come away understanding that using Elm isn’t just good
for applications, it’s good for people. If we can keep the developer’s personal
experiences in mind when building tools and libraries we will have a more
inclusive and accessible community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke Westby is a cofounder and partner at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblespark.com/&#34;&gt;HumbleSpark&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago, IL, USA. He is an
active member of the Elm community, helping to maintaining several open source
packages including elm-http-builder and elm-lang/core. He loves contributing to
the Elm community by speaking about the language, answering questions in the
Elm Slack, writing blog posts, and organizing the Chicago Elm Meetup. When he
is not thinking about code he likes to play the guitar, speed-run Metroid
Fusion, and watch far too much TV with his fiancée.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Feldman</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/richard-feldman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 10:27:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/richard-feldman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the most time-consuming bugs to track down are the ones where we look at
our application state and say &amp;ldquo;this shouldn’t be possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can use Elm’s compiler to rule out many of these bugs in the first place—but
only if we design our Models using the right techniques! This talk explores how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started using Elm, I wrote my Models roughly the same way I would
have in JavaScript. I was happy that I no longer got type mismatches, but I
still often found myself debugging how I’d gotten into an application state that
I’d thought was impossible. Over time I learned I could rule out many of these
bugs with more careful Model design, and my applications got more reliable as a
result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore the techniques I’ve learned to do exactly that. We’ll
look at how to use union types for more fine-grained control than records, how
to rule out the possibility of collections being unexpectedly empty, and how
exposing the right things within modules can preserve these guarantees across a
large code base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come see how we can use Elm’s compiler to take undesirable application states
from &amp;ldquo;ought to be impossible&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;actually impossible!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard is the author of &amp;ldquo;Elm in Action&amp;rdquo; from Manning Publications, and the
instructor for the Frontend Masters 2-Day Elm Workshop. When he’s not writing
about Elm, teaching Elm, speaking about Elm, or co-hosting the San Francisco Elm
meetup, he likes to take a break from his job of writing Elm code full-time as
an engineer at NoRedInk by kicking back and working on some of his open-source
Elm projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have said he’s &amp;ldquo;a fan of Elm,&amp;rdquo; but he’s not sure where they got that wild
idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ossi Hanhinen</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/ossi-hanhinen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 10:10:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/ossi-hanhinen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you come into grips with Elm as a language and prolific enough to start
using it in a real project? Awesome! Did you already have an idea of how you
would structure your application, handle authentication and maybe show
toast-like pop up messages in the UI? If not, this talk is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people know how to create small apps for fun in Elm. Some have crafted
larger things but felt they were missing something. Having done two larger
customer projects in Elm, I have some solid experience under my belt about
building big applications for production. In both projects, the initial folder
structure and the initial module architecture became untenable in a few months.
This talk is a down-to-earth lessons learned aimed for everyone who has done or
is planning on doing production applications using the language. I will
introduce strategies to overcome some of the common problems we have as frontend
engineers, but also share some war stories of times when things didn’t quite go
as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ossi is building apps for browsers to run and users to enjoy at Futurice. He
likes to constantly challenge his views on user interface programming, and
lately has gravitated towards functional programming and strong typing with Elm.
Ossi has started two separate customer projects (both of them ongoing) using the
language, making Futurice one of the first commercial users of Elm. He is also
the main person behind Elm Native UI, the open source project trying to make
building mobile apps with React Native possible in Elm, and Keyboard.Extra.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NoRedInk</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/noredink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:56:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/noredink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.noredink.com/jobs&#34;&gt;NoRedInk&lt;/a&gt; has the largest commercial Elm
codebase in the world, and has
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.noredink.com/post/136615783598/welcome-evan&#34;&gt;hired Elm creator Evan Czaplicki&lt;/a&gt;
to develop the language full-time. We spend almost all of our front-end coding
time writing Elm. Our software helps English teachers, and their students answer
millions of questions per day on our site. About half of our 15-person
engineering &lt;a href=&#34;http://noredink.com/about/team&#34;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; works remotely from around
the world, and the other half is in our San Francisco office.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.noredink.com/jobs&#34;&gt;We’re hiring&lt;/a&gt; for front-end, back-end, and ops.
No prior Elm experience necessary!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DailyDrip</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/dailydrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:56:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/dailydrip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailydrip.com/?utm_source=elm-conf&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=elm-conf-2016&#34;&gt;DailyDrip&lt;/a&gt;
makes learning easier. Every weekday you&amp;rsquo;ll get a bite-sized piece of something
awesome about a topic you are interested in. Best of all: it only takes five
minutes a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oasis Digital</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/oasis-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 14:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/oasis-digital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oasisdigital.com/&#34;&gt;Oasis Digital&lt;/a&gt; is a custom software development firm
in St. Louis, MO. We create high quality software and solve hard problems, to
help our customers thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About elm-conf</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 14:05:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Elm-conf is a new conference as of 2016. We want to promote Elm and the
ecosystem around it by bringing together the brightest minds in the community
for a day of mixing ideas and making connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who helped make elm-conf US a reality! Special thanks to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thestrangeloop.com&#34;&gt;Strange Loop&lt;/a&gt; for hosting the conference, to our
great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elm-conf.us/sponsor/&#34;&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt; for making it affordable, and of course the talk
selection committee: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jessitron&#34;&gt;Jessica Kerr&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rtfeldman&#34;&gt;Richard Feldman&lt;/a&gt;. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible
without you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-organizing-principles&#34;&gt;General organizing principles:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assume you know about Elm already. Beginner talks, while great, are more
appropriate for a general-interest conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thriving community is built on diversity. We encourage people from all
different backgrounds and walks of life to attend and speak. To ensure that all
are welcome, we follow and enforce a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thestrangeloop.com/policies.html&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;, to which all present
at the conference are expected to adhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community, not marketing. We don&amp;rsquo;t give the attendee list to any sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blind auditions. Talks are selected anonymously by a diverse talk selection
committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizers&#34;&gt;Organizers:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brian Hicks (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brianhicks&#34;&gt;@brianhicks&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joseph Hager (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ajhager&#34;&gt;@ajhager&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evan Czaplicki - Creator of Elm</title>
      <link>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/evan-czaplicki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 07:48:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.elm-conf.us/speaker/evan-czaplicki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Evan created Elm, a functional language for web programming. He is an open
source engineer at NoRedInk, where all front-end code is written in Elm these
days. He continues to develop the language, tools, and libraries full time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>